hamidashita kaze wo atsumete mitai na
I want to try and gather the unrestrained winds
nami no saki tsutatte kanata e kaketeku
I'll run toward the horizon alongside the wave crests
kakugo wa kimatteru
I've made my decision
michi wa tookutemo
even if there's a long way to go on that road
egaita mirai e tsudzuiteru
I'll continue towards the future I've planned
toki ga bokura wo sekashite kodou ga supiido agetetta
time rushes us, the heartbeat speeds up
yume no naka de mezametemo onaji hikari wo sagashita
when I woke in the middle of a dream, I kept searching for that same light
kagayaku hoshizora no shita kazoekirenai seiza to kage
under the shining star-lit sky, with countless constellations and shadows
sono saki ni kimi wa nani wo nani wo mitsumete iru darou
there was something beyond that, what were you gazing at?
nani wo mitsumete iru darou
what were you gazing at?
It's been a while
since I've eaten Ichiraku ramen!
Lately I've been away
from home on missions.
The bowl of ramen after a mission,
it spreads to every muscle of the body
and becomes energy for tomorrow.
If you eat ramen,
it drives fatigue away.
Ramen!
"TEMPORARILY CLOSED"
"Temporarily closed"?
No, it can't be.
I endured all the tough missions,
looking forward to Ichiraku ramen.
— I can smell ramen!
— What?
You're right!
Without a doubt,
ramen is being made in there!
Ramen!
Burn, Cauldron!
Mix, Stretch and Boil!!
This smell...
It's the smell of a soup
that's never been
on the Ichiraku menu before.
Then... it's temporarily closed
to develop a new menu?
Who's there?!
A large helping of miso char siu ramen!
With an egg please.
I see...
You were looking forward
to my ramen that much.
Sorry about that.
It's okay to develop a new menu,
but I wish you'd do it
after the shop is closed.
Since you came all this way.
Give this a taste.
Could this be...?
Ichiraku's new menu?!
Let's eat!
Wait a minute!
There are rules when you're eating
a new ramen for the first time.
Rule 1!
Before you do anything,
you must first have
a sip to taste the soup.
— Delicious!
Next, you have to coat the noodles
in soup and eat.
Huh? It seems like something
is missing...
Let's get to the point.
The noodles are outdone
by the soup!
This well-seasoned, rich soup
greatly surpasses
any of Ichiraku's previous soups!
But the noodles are
the same as always!
The balance is very bad.
I cannot give it a passing score!
That's what I thought.
Don't get so depressed.
Ayame, water! Water, please!
Huh? Where's Ayame?
With ramen like this...
I'll never be able to get Ayame
back from the Ryonin.
Old Man!
He's just overtired.
I had him drink an energy drink,
so after a little rest, he'll recover.
But I think he should take a break
from the shop for a while.
He's been using his arms too much.
Look how swollen this is.
Come to think of it,
before he fell,
he said something about Ryonin
or whatever
did something to Ayame, I think.
Ayame is his daughter, right?
— What's Ryonin?
— I don't know.
Ryonin,
he's referring to the Ninja Chef.
Huh? Ninja Chef?
Do you know about them, Choji?
I've heard rumors about them.
One of the problems Shinobi's confront
on missions is the problem of meals!
Normally Food Pills were brought
with them,
but the main role of those are
to supply nutrients.
They have no taste.
If they could eat delicious food
while on missions,
would the success rate of missions rise?
Based on that theory, was born...
The Ninja Chef... Ryonin!
But what do those Ninja Chef have
to do with Ayame?
They snatched her away...
What?!
What are you talking about?!
Give us the details!
It was two weeks ago...
{"ICHIRAKU RAMEN"
Welcome!
The large serving,
here's your order!
A good job as always, Teuchi!
Hakkaku!
His name is Hakkaku,
long ago we trained
at the same ramen shop...
{"CLOSED FOR BREAK"
He told me he is a Ninja Chef,
a Ryonin, these days.
Actually, I have a favor to ask you.
What is it? If it's something I can do,
I'll cooperate.
The phantom recipe
that I heard you developed...
Please turn it over to me!
Phantom recipe?
What are you talking about?
To a chef, a recipe is
more precious than life!
I understand why you want to hide it!
But... please! Give it to me!
I really had no clue.
But Hakkaku didn't believe me.
Ayame. Let's get to work
opening the shop.
What the...? What's this tray?
Ayame!
I have your daughter.
If you want her back,
hand over the phantom recipe!
Damn that Hakkaku!
Why didn't you contact
the Hokage right away?
The Hokage could...
If I did that, I don't know
what would happen to Ayame.
And he also wrote this
in the letter...
That if I can serve them
something impressive,
he'll give up on the phantom recipe
and return my daughter safe.
But you've got a way to win?
I don't know.
But a chef's challenged me
to a cooking match.
I have no choice but to do it.
So, that's why you're developing
new ramen.
I was able to make the soup
exactly how I wanted to.
But I just can't get the firm noodles
that go with the soup.
I can't get Ayame back like this!
The cooking match is tomorrow.
What am I going to do?
I can't imagine an Ichiraku
without Ayame.
Okay! Teuchi! We'll help you.
We'll make the best ramen...
And get Ayame back...
From the Ryonin!
You guys...
I'll teach you the basics
of making noodles.
Quickly mix the ingredients evenly.
If there are discrepancies,
there will be variations
in the taste of the noodles.
Next, knead it.
If you don't do this properly,
the noodles won't be firm.
Are you okay?
It's nothing. Don't worry about me.
And stretch the noodles!
It's important for them to be
of a uniform thickness!
So there will be no differences
after boiling...
Try it.
It's easy to say it,
but to actually make the noodles
is not so easy.
It takes five years to become
an accomplished chef in his own right.
To do it by the match tomorrow
is completely...
When it comes down to it,
I'll have to give up this decrepit body
of mine to them.
Teuchi...
you're not thinking about
when you lose, are you?
That's...
Because if we are doing this,
we're doing it with the intention
of winning!
I absolutely don't forgive people
who hold a girl captive!
Cooking comes from the heart.
Technique and experience
aren't everything!
No problem.
We'll show them the real strength
of the Shinobi of Leaf Village!
Sorry to make you wait, Hakkaku!
The phantom recipe?
You can't tell by looking at me?
I see. How foolish...
Let me tell you,
ramen like the stuff I ate
at your shop the other day can't win.
Is Ayame okay?
Father!
Ayame!
The emotional reunion comes
after the match.
I have a favor to ask.
Let me have some helpers.
I don't think those kids are up
to the task, but...
Well, that's okay.
Well, let's start the cooking match!
Let's see if you can satisfy
all of us Ninja Chef!
There are so many of them!
We don't have time to stand around.
Let's begin!
The preparation for the soup is done!
I'll prepare the ingredients
for the rest!
I'm leaving the noodles to you!
— Okay!
Listen. Our noodles determine
whether Ayame will return or not!
We cannot fail!
Seems like he's done a good job
with the soup...
The delicious aroma is wafting
over here.
Indeed, it's whetting my appetite.
The noodles are the problem!
Can those kids really make noodles
that will go with that soup?
First, mix the ingredients!
They're amateurs, I thought so!
You can't make decent noodles
with that hand movement!
We practiced making noodles all night!
But we didn't make the noodles
we wanted to by morning.
Even so, we have
to make perfect noodles!
Hey, hey. At least make us
something edible!
Quickly...
Uniformly...
Without discrepancies!
Next, knead it!
Hey, Sakura!
Look, it's Kakashi-sensei.
Don't play!
Sakura...
Ow! Sakura, you just can't control
your own crazy strength!
It's your fault for playing around
at a time like this!
This is...
the last of the ingredients.
No problem. This time,
let us show you we'll succeed!
Okay, I'm mixing.
Wait, Choji! Leave this to me!
— Naruto...
— Hey, Sakura...
We are Shinobi, right?
So, then, let's show them
the Ninja way to make noodles!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Rasengan! "Ichiraku" version!
What?! Mixing ingredients
with Chakra?!
No, that way he'll surely be able
to mix the ingredients uniformly!
And in micro units!
Sakura!
What?
Pervy Sage.
Naruto!
Shannaro!
What's this crazy strength...?!
If she does that,
the noodles will become super firm!
Okay, Sakura!
Choji!
I, too, am a Shinobi of Leaf Village!
Partial Expansion Jutsu: Both Hands!
What?!
What outstanding noodles!
If those noodles are added
to Teuchi's soup, this match would...
We cannot lose!
It's for the future of the Ninja Chef!
Now they just have to be boiled, Teuchi!
Okay! Leave it to me!
Wait a minute!
When the ramen is done,
who will you serve it to first?
Huh? Who...?
That's right. That's how it is!
That's how what is?
Among chefs,
there's a cardinal rule
not to be forgotten.
The first guest to arrive is
the first guest served!
No matter how delicious
the food you make is,
if you break this cardinal rule,
you're disqualified as a chef!
True, if a guy who came later
were eating before me,
then it would seriously piss me off.
There are 100 Ninja Chefs here.
They all showed up
at about the same time!
So, you have to serve ramen
to 100 people at the same time!
You're four people.
Can you really serve
at the same time?
I said we're Ninja, didn't I?
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
What?!
Now! Lift them!
Thanks for waiting. Here you go!
The taste is the issue!
If you don't satisfy us, you lose!
Delicious!
I've never had ramen this delicious.
— So, then...
— We win!
We did it!
The truth is...
we Ninja Chefs are
at the end of our rope.
End of your rope?
What do you mean by that?
We endeavored to make delicious meals
to eat during missions.
We thought to make delicious food
to fill your stomach
that can be eaten anywhere.
But we pursued taste too far.
It was too delicious,
people were compelled to overeat.
And as a result...
Ninja gained weight,
and it interfered with their missions.
And some people are now saying:
"We don't need
the Ninja Chefs anymore."
For us Ninja Chefs to continue,
we had to get our hands
on the phantom recipe out there
in the cooking world!
Recipe?
If we use this recipe,
we can improve the performance
of Shinobi without causing a burden.
There's such a recipe?
I hear, it's called the scum recipe.
The scum recipe?
We've gathered information
from everywhere.
As a result,
we learned that the scum recipe was
at "Ichiraku," which Teuchi runs.
What?!
I don't know!
There's no reason something
like that should be at my shop!
There's someone who heard it!
I've got the scum recipe
at my shop, so...
Oh, Teuchi...?
I might have that.
Are you serious?!
I thought so!
To be precise,
it's the scum-removal recipe.
Scum removal?
The trick to making delicious soup...
is how well you remove the scum.
So, I, too, studied a lot.
Eventually, I worked out a recipe
that can remove the scum effectively.
Usually it's called
the scum recipe for short.
I never thought
that this misunderstanding would arise.
That's a pretty big omission.
Gee, that's a stupid punch line.
We won the cooking match,
so keep your promise
and return Ayame!
That's right! Where is she?!
Father!
Ayame?
Ayame... is that you?
Can't you tell by looking?
But Ayame is like...
The food they make is
so delicious, I overeat.
Did I gain that much weight?
Ayame!
Ichiraku's new menu?
The thing we made
at the cooking challenge?
No, a diet ramen
that's popular among girls.
Diet ramen?
It's super popular!
Oh, come on in, Naruto.
You've regained your former shape.
It's thanks
to my father's diet ramen!
Huh? Where's your father?
Well, while he was joining me
in eating the diet ramen...
Hey, Naruto.
That's a little too thin.
kaze ga fuite aa
the wind blows
itai kienai omoi
the pain, the memories won't disappear
nani wo motte ikou ka
what should be brought along?
atsumete hitotsu
assemble them into a piece
nido to nai nido to nai
there is no second chance, never
suteru nante baka mitai
how foolish it is to throw away
mujaki ni natte aa
acting so innocently
imeeji
the images
kitto sore wa owaranai
it probably will not end
ai no mune kogase
burn that love-filled heart
sen no yume watare
sail across a thousand dreams
juuoumujin kakete
running freely
te ni tsukamu sekai
to take hold of the world in hand
kumo ga chigirete
the clouds scatter
hi ga mata ochite
the sun sets yet again
hitori no pareedo ga ugokidasu
the solo parade begins to move
bouken kichijitsu shinpaku joushou
adventure, lucky day, geart beat, rising
meian souguu seimei souai
decisive, encounter, life, mutual love
Does anyone have anything
to ask about this mission?
I've got a question!
Why should I have to go on
a mission with this group?
Okay, let's move on.
Everyone ready?
Hey, I've got a question!
As for the mission details,
we're to eliminate the Demon of the Ocean
in the Land of Oceans.
You guys are going to get
fired up for me
since you came to serve under me!
Just a minute.
Hey, listen to me!
Now, let's get going!
Stop complaining and
just come with me!
Listen to me, I say.
Listen! Listen! Listen!
Next time:
"Memory, the Lost Page."